Curriculum Vitae	Miri Nichol Data Scientist, Physicist & Art Forger	
contact citizenship	kiri.nichol@gmail.com Github : small-yellow-duck.github.io	
Career goal	I use data to tell a story. I build mathematical models and software tools to describe and understand patterns in images and data. I like to stumble on to new problems, clarify vague problems and make abstract problems concrete. I like to learn from my colleagues and to share my own expertise.	
Education		

Ph.D. Physics, Leiden University, The Netherlands M.Sc. Physics, McMaster University, Canada 2006 B.Sc (Hons) Physics, minor English Literature, University of British Columbia, Canada 2004

Skills

programming	Python. I have substantial prior experience in Delphi, Matlab, IDL, Labview and Fortran. I can ask for		
	directions and order coffee with C++, JavaScript and html. I run my GPU code on an Amazon i		
data analysis, stats	analysis, stats Matlab, R, IDL, Maple, Mathematica, ImageJ		
machine learning	machine learning scikit-learn, nltk, theano.		
database	base pandas, xml, SQL (SQLAlchemy), DICOM, Excel		
lab tools	Experimental design, particle tracking, automatic image segmentation, electronic data acquisition		
	with Labview		
math	statistics, linear algebra, differential equations, waveform analysis		
business skills	project management, writing technical reports (Word, LateX) and presentations (Powerpoint).		
	"Kiri is one of the best talkers I know." / "Kiri can talk to anyone."		
languages	English (native), Dutch (fluent)		

.... Looking for something not on the list? I am always keen to learn.

Experience

July 2013-Data Scientist, Programmer & Generalist Hack, small-yellow-duck.github.io • I love tackling problems on **Kaggle.com**. I have **Kaggle Master** status. (Python, sklearn, pandas) • Developed circadelic.appspot.com – an app for generating colourful circle packings from the palette in a photograph. The app includes a numpy-only implementation of k-means which runs on Google App Engines. (Python, html, JavaScript) Developed victory-boogie-woogie.appspot.com – an app for faking images that look like Piet Mondrian's famous painting. (Python, html, JavaScript) 2011-2013

- Postdoctoral Researcher, Radiotherapy Department of the Dutch Cancer Institute (NKI)
- Developed software for implementing and evaluating new image-based tools and treatment strategies in radiotherapy. (Delphi, Matlab, Python)
- Quality assurance: assessing the consistency and accuracy of deformable registration and automatic segmentation routines for CT images. As part of this problem, I developed meaningful metrics for comparing and evaluating delineated organs.
- Managed a DICOM database with data from different hospitals.

2007-2011

Ph.D. Researcher, Granular and Complex Matter Lab, Leiden University

- Modeled and analyzed fluctuations in sheared granular matter (IDL, Labview)
- Described viscous drag and Archimedes's Rule in sheared granular matter. (IDL,Labview)
- Developed rheometry tools and instrumentation (... a rubber bath duck)

2010-2011

Visiting Researcher, Complex Matter Lab, North Carolina State University

- Generalized models from statistical mechanics to describe the motion of 150 air hockey pucks.
- Developed and optimized particle tracking software to determine the position of the air hockey pucks. (Matlab)

2007

Visting Researcher, Nanoscale Devices Lab, University of Canterbury

- Modeled deposition of metal clusters for the production of nanoscale wires (Maple)
- Performed electron microscopy to image clusters deposited on substrates

2004-2006

M.Sc. Researcher, Superconductivity Theory, McMaster University

• Developed software to map the electronic states of endohedral doped fullerene molecules for use in quantum computing. (Fortran, C++)

Teaching Experience

- Introduction to Labview, lab instruction and course development (Leiden)
 Statistical Physics, tutorial teaching assistant (Leiden)
 - First-Year Physics , tutorial teaching assistant (U Canterbury)
- First-Year Physics for Engineers, lab and tutorial teaching assistant (McMaster)
- First-Year Physics for Life Sciences, tutorial teaching assistant (McMaster)
- Physics for Arts and Science, tutorials, project guidance (McMaster)

team of Physsoc members to write the solutions in Latex.

Volunteer Experience

2008-2010	Lab tours, Open Days (Leiden) 2008 - 2011
2006-2008	May@Mac, Physics Paper Triathalon (McMaster)
2008-2010	Physics Olympics (UBC) 2001 - 2004
	I enjoy planning and running demos and activities for schoolchildren. By the end of my PhD, my
	spoken Dutch was fluent enough to ask and answer questions.
2004-2006	Social Coordinator, McMaster Physics Grad Student Council 2004-2006
2002-2004	VP Academic, Physics Students Society, UBC
	I managed the sale and production of solution manuals for first-year physics exams. I coordinated a

Awards & Distinctions

2013	2 nd prize, setup.nl's "Elegante Algoritmes" competition
	(victory-boogie-woogie.appspot.com)
2000, 2003, 2004	UBC Faculty of Science Dean's List
1999-2004	UBC Chancellor's Entrance Scholarship

References are available on request